♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ Somewhere in time and space ♪
♪ Mike Nelson
and his robot pals ♪
♪ Are caught in a nasty place ♪
♪ They try to survive
the wrath of Pearl ♪
♪ Just an evil gal
who wants to rule the world ♪
♪ From her castle below,
she sets her sights above ♪
♪ Just to torture
all the captives ♪
♪ On the Satellite of Love ♪
MIKE: Get me down.
♪ I'll send him cheesy movies ♪
-♪ The worst I can find ♪
-ALL: ♪ La, la, la ♪
PEARL: ♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
-♪ And I'll monitor his mind ♪
-♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Now, keep in mind,
Mike can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help
of his robot friends ♪
MAN: Robot Roll Call,
- Cambot!
-You're on!
-MAN: Gypsy!
-Oh, my stars!
-MAN: Tom Servo!
-Check me out!
-MAN: Croooow!
-I'm different!
♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
-♪ And other science facts ♪
-ALL: ♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself,
It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000! ♪
[ Doors closing ]
-CROW: Ooh, wow.
-Hmm, our onion blossomer
-works really good.
-Hey, Mike.
Look, we finally got our onion
blossomer from Lily
-and Vernon.
-Oh, wow.
So, you onion-blossomed
a bowling bowl and...
-Yup.
-I see a caulking gun
-and a-- and a shoe?
-Of course.
Blossoming makes everything
taste great.
-Yeah.
-Well, just about anything
can be a pleasing side dish
with lamb or Salisbury steak.
Doesn't everything
just look delicious?
Everything looks blossomed.
Is that my wallet there?
TOM: You bet, blossomed
and batter-dipped.
-Yummy.
-Great.
Well, we'll be right back.
Doesn't it all
just look so good?
Ooh, I wanna try some plunger.
Plunger, yum.
[ Music playing ]
Hmm, now, this is a blossom
worth eating.
Now try it with my delicious
dipping sauce.
-Hmm.
-Hey, looks good.
-What you got there?
-Your head.
Yeah-- but you blossomed
and fried my head?
Oh, lighten up.
You didn't even miss it.
Try it with my dipping
sauce, Tom.
But your blossomed and fried
[ Sniffs ] my [ Sniffs ]
hey, is that Peppercorn Ranch?
-Uh-huh.
-Hmm.
Oh, Pearl's calling.
Mike, Crow, snack,
I've done it.
This experiment will thrust me
to the highest
ranks of mad science.
All done.
We've soldered tiny electrodes
to all the speech
and motor sensors
of Bobo's brain.
It will either kill him
or allow us
to control his every motion.
Oh, and it's portable.
All controlled
by this universal remote
we got at Target for nine bucks.
Here, try it out, Pearl.
Oh, let's start with a few
simple motor skills,
a left hand twitch.
-Okay.
-A nice knee jerk.
Oh, try the self-strangling
macro I put in there.
Lovely.
Oh, okay.
And now, my favorite,
"Perform a stupid
soft shoe grab
cattle prod, apply to self
while singing "Tonight"
from the charming libretto
of
No, please.
It will kill me the--
♪ Tonight, tonight... ♪
[ Screams ] merde,
that hurts me.
Try it out, Mike.
All you need is a universal
learning remote
with the control code for Bobo
found in the manual.
♪ Officer Krupke. ♪
Okay, Pearl, we got it.
Go ahead there, Crow.
Okay. Let's see.
Sanyo 02, Hitachi 19.
Here it is, Bobo.
-Press 14.
-Okay.
-Fourteen.
-Yeah.
Enter. Okay.
What should we do?
Oh, I got it, Mike.
Come here, come here.
-[ Whispers ]
-Yeah?
Good. That's good.
Okay.
-We're just gonna...
-Right, right.
And just-- enter.
Sorry, Pearl.
Can't help myself.
Man, that must hurt.
Oops, sorry, Brain Guy,
all involuntary
muscular actions.
Now to involuntarily bring Mike
and the bots down.
-It works.
-Okay, great.
Now, I'll just have Bobo
tie up Pearl.
-Perfect.
-And Brain Guy.
So they can't get-- uh-oh.
Uh-oh, what?
I hit the sleep function.
-No. Mike.
-Mike.
Good one, Nelson.
You almost got me.
I have a little work to do.
But first, let's get the monkey
all nice and punished.
Pluck all nose hairs
with rusty pliers.
Brain Dead,
let's send these guys
"Track of the Moon Beast."
It stars nobody
and features nothing.
I hope you gag on it.
-Oh.
-Yeah.
Well, we tried anyway.
Hey, at least we got
my head to snack on.
Yeah, I guess.
Oh, we'll have to bring it
into the theater.
Now we got movie sign.
CROW: Don't forget
my delicious dipping sauce.
SERVO: Okay.
[ Doors opening ]
MIKE: [ Sighs ]
SERVO: Oh, I have a feeling
this Cinema Shares
won't give us
a very good return.
MIKE: Inside Al Gore's head.
-Speaking of.
-CROW: Here is one
of the tiny men
who operate the dials
on your stove.
MIKE: What an elaborate setup
just to peep on his neighbor.
CROW: Do you really want
your movie to start this way?
SERVO: Some burnt toast
is heading toward the sun.
MIKE: Who wants a light bulb?
Light bulb here.
Come on.
Two dollars.
Got a light bulb.
CROW: Come on now, Earl.
You said you were just gonna
make a short announcement
about parking.
SERVO:
He's a lousy version of...
[ Servo mimics Enigma's
"Return To Innocence" ]
hey, hey, hey.
MIKE: Ginger Baker of the tribe.
CROW: Icarus.
Pull out, Icarus.
SERVO: Bring your 4x4 down
to the Track of the Moon Beast.
CROW: How green was my credits?
MIKE:
Are you hoping a jackrabbit
will just pop up
and spice up their credits?
SERVO: I don't see Brian Hamill
as still photographer.
I thought he got laid off.
Wrong.
CROW: Man, the producer got
the hell assisted out of him.
MIKE: Fitzhugh Emerson III
of the Moon Beast Emersons.
SERVO: Got a creepy feeling
that this was filmed
at the Spahn Ranch.
CROW: Hawkeye Pierce
returns to the MASH unit.
MIKE: Yeah, I got a finger
for you, William.
SERVO: A lonely beat
for a motorcycle cop.
MIKE: Frank there
is a child of the universe,
no less than the trees.
CROW: Please put your dick ash
out in the ash tray.
Thank you.
MIKE: Well, where's the crowd?
And where the hell
did my ramp go?
SERVO: Movie's mostly him
winterizing his bike.
CROW: We're gonna have
to practice some Zen
and the art of watching
motorcycle maintenance.
MIKE: He got that bike cheap
from Gary Busey.
SERVO: Okay.
Why did he bury his shirt?
MIKE:
Dug up a toilet seat? Well.
CROW: Huh.
Ah, he's in boot camp
for umpire training.
SERVO: It's a tusk
from a miniature pachyderm.
MIKE:
Ha, a rare sliver of concrete
from the Eisenhower Epoch.
CROW: I have found
an inscription.
It says, Fiestaware.
MAN: [ Shouts ]
SERVO: That's a dull razor.
MIKE: Sorry to be so naughty.
We're just badlands, I guess.
CROW: I saw the Stones
here, man.
MAN: [ Shouts ]
SERVO: What?
What are you looking for?
-Hi, Paul.
-PAUL: Johnny.
MIKE: Surprise guest star,
Don Ho.
PAUL: Johnny Longbow.
-SERVO: Johnny Longbone?
-Johnny, what...
Sorry for rushing
the Halloween season.
It was too good to resist.
What?
You can come out now.
Show's over.
SERVO: Ha, ha, ha, pointless
confusing pranks are fun.
Ha, ha.
Count Dracula at your service.
And better known on campus
as Budd Keeler.
-MIKE: Butt healer?
-And Janet Price.
Hi. Please do forgive us.
These, I'm afraid,
are two of my students
at the university.
Unfortunately, I'm saddled
with them
for my summer field course.
Just as you were
saddled with me.
CROW: Stop touching each other.
All right.
You decided to switch
from anthropology to mineralogy
at the graduate level.
MIKE: Man, remember?
Until that point I thought
you had a fair degree of sense.
MIKE: Oh, man,
that was great.
Was it you that made
that god-awful sound?
That was me, I'm afraid.
He also does bird calls.
Just don't get him started.
Janet, like I keep telling you,
an anthropology major these days
should have
more than one talent.
[ Mimics bird call ]
That's a talent?
Bird call?
SERVO: I borrowed my outfit
from Doc Severinsen.
I'm Kathy Nolan.
Paul, Paul Carlson.
SERVO: Get into the line-up.
Good.
Don't tell me you're a student.
Ms. Nolan's doing
a picture story
on the religious customs
of the tribes around here,
especially of my own people.
That's why Budd happened
to have a ceremonial mask.
It was my idea.
I borrowed the mask
from the collection
at the reservation
to do some mood shots
on location out here.
But when we were heading back,
and I saw you and Prof. Salinas
explained you were a friend,
well, I'm afraid the bright idea
of using it for practical jokes.
-CROW: Okay.
-And getting some shots
of your reaction was my idea.
Thanks. I'm glad to know.
MIKE:
Knowledge equals gladness.
I'm afraid we got more reaction
than I bargained for.
I won't use the shot.
That's a promise.
Am I forgiven?
CROW: Only if you stop
explaining it.
Of course, Ms. Nolan.
Kathy to my friends.
We are friends.
MIKE: Look, what do you want
from me?
We are, Kathy.
CROW:
Puller of ineffectual pranks.
We were just on our way
to Prof. Salinas' place
at the reservation.
He's promised us
an authentic Indian summer.
-Won't you join us?
-I'd like to if it's--
if it's all right
with Johnny Longbow.
It's all right with me.
No problem at all.
Just follow my car.
SERVO: I'll explain the joke
more at lunch.
Why do call him
Johnny Longbow?
That's his Indian name,
his tribal one.
MIKE: Like Wahoo McDaniels.
It translates "Warrior's bow
that reaches long to its mark."
CROW: Oh, is he seeing anyone?
Actually he handles a bow
like one of his ancestors.
SERVO: I approve.
The impact on the moon
has set off a shower
of fragments
mixed with pieces
of the asteroid.
SERVO: More TV, anyone?
Some of these
small fragments
will enter Earth's
atmosphere tonight.
But they will
undoubtedly explode
into nothing more
than a harmless shower
of tiny meteorites,
according to NASA station.
The greatest concentration
for the
meteor shower
over the southwest region
of the United States.
This meteor shower will be,
however, quite harmless
according to the statement
from NASA
and likely to provide
nothing more
than a spectacular
sight in the sky.
SERVO: I'm Kent Brockman.
And that's the story
of the awesome collision
on the moon today.
This is Gary Kanin
from our news center
in Albuquerque.
CROW: Gary's a great guy.
I didn't schedule
a meteor shower
as part of the evening
entertainment
at the reservation.
That should be quite a sight.
BUDD: Oh, this is a great meal,
professor.
JANET: That's a great stew.
What's in it?
-Oh, a lot of things.
-SERVO: Rattlesnake, Velveeta.
Chicken, corn,
green peppers
chili, onions.
MIKE: Hair.
Well, it's an old recipe
around here.
[ Music playing ]
I'd like to get some
night shots of this area.
SERVO: I'll give you a night
shot of an area.
Well, if you don't mind me
tagging along.
I know a few great spots.
But they're pretty far away.
CROW: So we'd have
to go there naked.
MIKE: Oh, thank you
for guiding me,
or I would've walked
in any random direction.
SERVO: Hey, they're going
for night shots at 12:00 noon.
CROW: Yeah.
[ Gasps ]
What's that?
CROW: It's a Gran Fury,
about 1973.
That is a lizard.
SERVO: You girl.
Sorry, things like that
scare me.
MIKE: Yes, I know.
You get used to lizards here.
They're quite common.
That's why tribes in this area
have so many legends
-about lizards.
-CROW: Ask me to tell one,
-ask me tell one.
-BUDD: Like what, for instance?
Oh, such as the story of Lizard
and Coyote for instance.
SERVO: Oh, boy, hunker down.
In the days before
there were men on earth.
Sounds like it's going to be
the Navajo version of Genesis.
Ignore him, professor.
I'd like to hear the story.
CROW: I just want some peyote.
They'll have no effect
on your grades.
I don't expect it to.
I'd just like to hear it.
Well, one day.
SERVO: [ Snores ]
Before Man walked on earth,
Lizard and Coyote
were having an argument
about what shape
man would take.
MIKE: They fought and died
in the end.
-Lizard won the argument.
-CROW: And Coyote
-battled Roadrunner.
-They finally agreed
that man's hands
would be shaped like Lizard's,
four fingers and a thumb.
BUDD: Hey, that's right.
JANET: Was that the end
of the story?
-Not quite.
-SERVO: Not even close.
Coyote drove a hard bargain.
He agreed that man's hands
would be shaped like Lizard's
rather than his paws,
but only, only...
MIKE: If he retained
the film rights.
...if man would be mortal.
CROW: Uh-huh.
Do you know Billy Jack?
And never again
try to be like Lizard.
MIKE: And so
they called it maize.
CROW: Stop talking,
Johnny Longbone.
You can see
quite a distance up here.
CROW: She's wearing
a frosted denim onesie.
Although we've got a lot more
air pollution than we used to.
MIKE: Since we ate
Johnny's stew.
PAUL: That's Albuquerque
over there.
SERVO: Before electricity.
PAUL: And that road leads
to Santa Fe, northeast,
and the river's over there.
-Paul, where are we exactly?
-SERVO: I'm telling you,
what do you want,
longitude and latitude?
I'm sorry, we're on the top
of Sandia Crest.
It's 10,678 feet,
up or down.
CROW: Does that affect
my thighs?
Depending on where you are
and your point of view.
CROW: Oh, I've never had
one of those.
Yeah, I like to come up here
at night.
SERVO: And hock loogies
on passing cars.
It's one of my favorite
places on earth.
SERVO: After Branson.
It's always so peaceful,
-so quiet.
-CROW: So hot pants.
Sorry, sorry.
Somehow,
both the rest of my life.
MIKE: That's a pretty low bar,
really, though.
CROW: Well, they're not
making out yet.
SERVO: Well, I guess
Wilt Chamberlain's in town
or something.
Right on schedule.
SERVO: Johnny, are you
mouthing something?
CROW: Tree.
Paul, what's wrong?
What is it?
CROW: They're heading
for the ovum.
MIKE: Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I've used that
-during meteor showers.
-CROW: Tease.
Okay. Yeah.
Paul, the meteors are gone,
-Paul.
-Paul, are you all right?
-What happened?
-CROW: She gets off the ground
saying "What happened" a lot.
Meteorite,
a lunar meteorite.
A meteorite?
CROW: A lunar meteorite?
We heard about it
earlier on TV.
Yes, but here?
Well, we're right in the area
where they're due to fall.
CROW: They have every right
to kill us.
I guess we can consider
ourselves lucky.
MIKE: I mean,
soon I'll be able to consider
myself having
gotten lucky, right?
What's the matter?
You've got a scratch
or something
-on your forehead.
-CROW: That's where my ear
used to be.
I had it moved.
I don't feel anything.
Oh, no, don't touch it,
let me do that.
CROW: Oh, words
every guy wants to hear.
I must have bumped it
when we hit the dirt.
MIKE: You don't have
to scrub it.
Let me clean it up anyway.
See, you were bleeding.
That's nothing.
SERVO: Let's celebrate
by littering.
Hey, Kathy,
-look at that.
-MIKE: It's that tissue
I just threw.
Hey, hi, tissue.
SERVO: What ancient
civilization could've left
this motorcycle here?
[ Makes noise ]
It'll make a great souvenir,
my own personal moon rock.
[ Gasps ] Moon rock?
Oh, wow.
PAUL: Did I say something wrong?
No, but you just reminded me
I'm supposed to go
into town tomorrow.
There's a NASA exhibit
at the university
and I'm supposed to cover it.
That's a great idea.
SERVO: Um, without you.
We'll go to the exhibit,
then we'll have some supper.
CROW: Then a dab of sex.
Then we'll go out afterwards.
And just in case the moon rock
hasn't cooled off.
CROW: We'll just give it
a little time out.
MIKE: Well, it's not cool
and now I have no plan.
It's cool enough to travel now.
CROW: It'd be cooler
if it played the bongos
or wrote poetry.
Have you got a first aid kit
in that bag?
A few things. Why?
I'm still worried
about that cut on your head.
It could get infected.
MIKE: If you keep pawing
at it, then, yeah.
Look, I don't live far
from here
and I've got
all kinds of antiseptic
in my medicine cabinet
in my place.
SERVO: Dozens,
no, hundreds of antiseptics.
-Your place?
-My place.
MIKE: I call it
'Antiseptic Manor.
Fine, your place, then.
CROW: Not his place,
fornicators.
MIKE: New Puffs Plus
with Strontium-90.
SERVO: I share
an effeciency apartment
with a bunch of other guys.
CROW: I did that with my mind.
MIKE: Okay. Now watch
how hard I hit the wall.
SERVO: Should I leave
the bike running
so I can take you
right home afterwards?
MIKE: Hey, he's got a nice
two-car living room.
SERVO: Mm-hmm.
Both look so furtive
and uncomfortable.
It must be love.
MIKE: That's one big French
press up there.
I gather nobody's home.
My mother's in Europe,
she travels a lot.
CROW: All this,
and he lives with his mother?
-Wow.
-SERVO: Hmm.
Do you hang up
every centerfold you get?
MIKE: Why do you keep a picture
of Army Archerd
on your nightstand?
♪ When will our eyes meet, ♪
♪ when will I see? ♪
SERVO: Where's your hair
coloring station?
MIKE: Yup,
this is my corner fireplace.
Now that the real Paul Carlson
has stood up,
what do you think?
SERVO: You can sit back down.
I won't be needing his services.
I think
you spend a lot of your life
being lonely.
MIKE: No, I got my chat rooms.
When your parents are divorced,
you get used to it.
I'd like you to meet a friend
of mine.
SERVO: Could you at least
kiss me first?
Strom Thurmond.
Hey, his name is Ty.
Ty?
Short for Tyrannosaurus.
Sounds like something
in a museum.
It is, usually.
CROW: But he's got
the night off.
Ty looks a lot like a dinosaur.
Or like the dragon Indians
call Amhuluk.
Thank you for introducing me
to your friend.
Well, I hope
he didn't frighten you.
MIKE: Then scratch
the maggot collection, I guess.
Paul.
SERVO: You're a lizard-loving
freak and I got to go.
It's us
I'm really frightened about.
CROW: We're an icky couple.
Kathy.
SERVO: Let me explain
by augering my tongue
into your mouth.
[ Music playing ]
[ Doors closing ]
CROW: [ Screams ]
[ Laughs ] Hi, Mike.
Sorry for rushing
the Halloween season, Mike.
It was just too good to resist.
You can come out now.
SERVO: [ Laughs ] Count Dracula
at your service.
Hi, do forgive us.
We also do bird calls.
[ Makes noise ]
That's a talent, bird calls?
It was my idea, Mike.
I made the mask earlier
to do some mood shots
on location here in the SOL,
but when we decided to break
for a beverage,
Servo saw you here
and explained to me
that you were up here
on the bridge eating pea pods.
And since we had the mask,
well, I'm afraid the bright idea
of using the mask
for a practical joke,
and then subsequently
documenting your reaction
to our practical joke on film,
was my idea.
I'm afraid I got a little more
reaction than I bargained for.
You bet.
I won't use the shot, Mike,
that-- that's a promise.
Look, I'm sorry, Mike,
I really am.
It's just that since
we had the mask,
it was, you know,
hard to resist doing,
you know,
a little practical joke there
and rushing the--
rushing the Halloween season
and all.
I mean, I didn't expect
such a huge reaction,
so, you know,
and it was my idea,
so I'm really--
I'm really sorry, Mike.
I won't use the film, I promise.
Really, really, Mike.
Please forgive me.
I just got so much more
than I bargained for.
I... [ Cries ]
Please, Mike, I beg you.
I'll never rush
the Halloween season again.
We'll be right back.
Just, you know, mood shots,
practical joke, I made them.
I hate myself.
[ Music playing ]
MIKE: Rocks served on a bed
of garbage bags.
CROW: Smile, Paul's ass.
Paul?
Paul, what happened?
SERVO: I keep seeing a woman
with a yellow
shrink-wrapped area.
Wow.
I guess I blacked out.
MIKE: Excuse me,
you African-Americaned out.
I'm okay.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I just need some fresh air.
SERVO: No, I'm trapped
in a loveless
one-day relationship.
[ Music playing ]
CROW: Who is that? Huh?
Ah, we-- we've stumbled
into an Eagles concert.
It's a nightmare!
MIKE: Shelley Duvall.
♪ My voice's been
getting froggy ♪
♪ I've been smoking
too damn much ♪
SERVO: He stole
Robin Gibb's head.
♪ Singing songs
to the sun that's rising ♪
♪ Rhyming words I
cannot touch ♪
CROW: Like purple and orange.
♪ Oh, I've been
wandering in circles ♪
♪ With just a guitar
in my hand ♪
SERVO: [ Makes noise ]
♪ Playing one
too many barrooms ♪
♪ And drinking
more than I can stand ♪
CROW: Marcia Brady on backup.
Both:
♪ Won't you bring
your love to me? ♪
-MIKE: Get it yourself.
-BOTH:
Servo:
♪ Add flavor to my meat ♪
Both:
CROW: [ Grunts ]
I am gonna throw up
if he sings one more bar.
[ Grunts ]
You'd be a lot better off
if we take you home
-right now.
-MIKE: Hey, look behind
Longbow, there's Waldo.
-CROW: Waldo.
-I'm going home.
♪ I'm hung out in Chicago ♪
♪ With a California mind ♪
Mike:
♪ And refused to wash
my stringy hair ♪
Oh, no, the snaggletooth
folk rocker
followed them home.
Man:
-SERVO: Eww.
-
♪ Funky bar rooms
and drinking ♪
-
-crow:
Both:
Servo:
♪ California lady ♪
♪ She's the one
that I wanna see ♪
♪ My California lady ♪
-MIKE: Who?
-BOTH:
CROW: Sorry,
I didn't catch that. Who?
-
-CROW: Oh.
The original
Smashing Pumpkins.
I'm just not sure,
leaving him alone.
-It's the best way.
-MIKE: No care
is the best care.
Paul's still learning
a lot of things.
Such as?
Such as how to accept
help from other people.
CROW: And, um...
that's it.
He's used to doing things
right out for himself.
SERVO: Of himself, at himself.
He's been a loner a long time.
It's not easy to change.
-Even so--
-Tell you what.
CROW: You finish crocheting
your dress.
If Paul calls me
during the night,
SERVO: I'll roll over and say,
"What?"
I'll call you
and come pick you up.
How's that?
I'll buy that.
MIKE: You know, her outfit
started out as a baby blanket
then she just added a bra to it.
CROW: By the way,
my car runs on green peppers,
corn, chicken, onions.
-And if Paul calls me first?
-Yes?
MIKE: Hey, interest rates go up?
I don't know. What?
[ Engine revving ]
MIKE: [ Grunts ]
California lady.
SERVO: Why did I switch
to mineralogy?
CROW: Nice place,
no atmosphere at all.
SERVO: Badum-tss.
He opens his curtain
and immediately
gets hit by Skylab.
MIKE: Man, he's out of shape.
Drawing back the curtain
shouldn't be that much work.
CROW: Close the curtains,
I got to get up early tomorrow
and eat roaches.
CROW:
I'm the Jim Morrison king.
MIKE: He sure gave that lizard
a lot of headroom.
CROW: Maybe he has
a trampoline in there.
SERVO: Man,
I feel like I listened
to '70s folk rock last night.
CROW: Hi, I'm here
for the misbegotten.
SERVO: Hmm, I should do
another rep with the curtains.
CROW: Hmm, maybe the lizard
would be interested in my chest.
MIKE: Well, now I can't
get back to sleep either.
What do you wanna do?
CROW: Well, I need to induce
vomiting, so here goes.
♪ California lady... ♪
Servo:
♪ Don't wanna be ♪
Thing, get down from--oh.
CROW:
Filmed through chocolate milk.
MIKE: Dennis the Menace's dad
really hit the skids.
Oh, no.
CROW: Hmm, what haven't
we seen in this movie yet?
Oh, right, a scrawny, drunken
bowler's ass cheeks,
thank you.
SERVO: Hmm, I think
I threw a cigarette butt
down here last week.
CROW: He has an M.A.
in bowling from Duke.
[ Music playing ]
MAN: That concludes
the national news.
Now turning to the news
of the local Albuquerque...
SERVO: Is that Dick Gregory?
MAN: Twenty-five people
were stranded this afternoon
-for over four hours...
-SID: I dropped my keys.
-Come on, open up.
-CROW: Ah, good,
the bigger couch
is finally here.
MAN: ...due to a severe thunder
and lightning storm
which swept through
the Sandia range
at approximately 2:00
this afternoon.
SERVO: Can we have more
annoying ambient sound, please?
SID: I don't wanna stand out
here all night.
-CROW: [ Mimicking ]
-SID: Open up, please.
Come on, open up.
MIKE: Oh, I miss my mom.
-CROW: Yeah.
-Oh, go to hell, Sid.
I told you what was gonna happen
when you came home again
from that bowling alley drunk.
I'm going to bed
and you can just sleep it off
out there.
Go to hell.
CROW: No, that would mean
letting him in the house.
MIKE: Well, I'll go back
to the bowling alley,
sleep in the ball return.
Who's there?
SERVO: The paperboy coming
for his Christmas tip.
Don't take my face grease.
[ Screaming ]
SERVO: I left my rosin bag
at the bowling alley.
[ Grunting ]
[ Screaming ]
CROW: Damn,
my underwire popped out.
Ouch.
SERVO: [ Singing
David Bowie's "Fame" ]
MIKE: Oh, Gourmet Express
delivered her tomato bisque
under the door.
SERVO: What's your name?
What's your name?
CROW: Well, there goes
another one.
Man, do I tear through
the husbands.
SERVO: I picked at it.
[ Screams ]
CROW: We'll be right back.
See?
Thank Screamer
for bringing the professor.
-SERVO: Giddyup.
-Well, Mack?
SERVO: Bone, how are you?
What happened here?
A killing. A messy one.
-SERVO: He did it.
-The medical examiner's
report being phoned in?
I'll make sure I'll have a copy
on your desk
when you're back in.
Good. Let me have copies
of the other reports, too.
-All of them.
-Yes, sir.
Fine.
Check in the house
and see if you can lend a hand.
CROW: Yup, just call me
Lt. Half-a-beef.
Now, I'll tell you why,
exactly why I asked you here.
I was wondering.
It sounded urgent.
It's because I need
an opinion from you.
MIKE: Do you like this outfit?
My field is in medicine.
You know that, Mack.
I know.
What's up?
One problem with being a cop
is that eventually
you think you've seen
everything.
Well, this morning
I found out I was wrong.
This is different.
Which one is him?
MIKE: Pick whichever one
you want.
The woman had a weak heart
and what she saw
when she opened the door
apparently finished her.
There's no report
of any violence on her
but take a look at the man.
SERVO: He is scrumptious.
What kind of thing
would cut up someone like that?
CROW: Martin Yan?
Could've been
a mountain lion, Mack.
No, Johnny, it's not that easy.
MIKE:
I knew you'd let me down.
I'm gonna show you
something one of my men
found at the back of the house.
SERVO: Snuggle up
and come with me.
Whatever killed Harris
must've tripped over
the garden hose
and grabbed at the side
of the house for support.
CROW: Then they dressed
a pencil as a cop.
Take a break.
I'll check it.
-You're right.
-MIKE: Someone's testing
-paint colors.
-It wasn't made
by a mountain lion.
That mark was made
by a human hand.
Well, I would agree with you
except for one thing.
-SERVO: You're wrong.
-You tell me
what kind of human
makes a footprint like that.
Now you get the picture again?
MIKE: You see now
why I patronize you?
When I got that radio call,
I thought someone had made
a real goof.
When I saw Harris...
CROW: I said,
"Hello, Harris."
...I had to believe it.
Harris was killed
by some kind of thing that...
MIKE: That killed him.
...was nearly seven feet tall,
had hands with claws
on the fingers.
SERVO: Spats and a top hat.
And walked on feet
like I've never seen before.
CROW: No, wait,
they were my feet.
That's why I had
to bring you here, Johnny.
MIKE: To make me look competent
by comparison.
Now, you're right,
this is not some kind
of medical problem.
I don't know what kind
of problem it is.
CROW: It's hard.
That's all I know.
You're an anthropologist,
Johnny.
I thought, well just maybe...
SERVO: You'd anthropologize.
...you might be able
to help us with this.
Well, I can tell you...
MIKE: About my stew.
...I've seen a track
like that before.
MACK: Where?
In a museum,
a fossil track,
several million years old.
CROW: You wanna throw in
a verb anywhere, Johnny?
Have your men made
a plastic cast of the track?
MACK: Hmm.
You might get a better answer
from the paleontology
department at the university.
SERVO: Or the meat department
at Ralphs.
The department head, Deets,
he's a friend of mine.
Let's go, now.
The casting should be ready.
CROW: J.C. Penney hooker wear,
for the casual hooker
at work, rest or play.
SERVO: Hey,
I'm wearing terry cloth,
you guys need
anything absorbed?
Whee, la, la, la, la, la
[ Laughing ] whee.
-Wake up.
-CROW: Come on, it's pink day.
-SERVO: There's another meteor
headed for your skull.
I decided to make
breakfast for us
while you hit the showers.
SERVO: I'm gonna make
pink eggs for breakfast
[ Laughing ] whee.
Paul!
Mike:
GENE: I agree
with Professor Salinas.
Your casting here is that
of the left hind foot
of some form of reptile,
some very, very large lizard.
I still can't believe
that there are lizards that big
in New Mexico or anywhere else
for that matter.
Sorry, Capt. McCabe,
you're wrong about that.
CROW: Thanks, Brigham Young.
There is a lizard
we call Varanus komodoensis.
There's some photos of him
over in the paleontology lab.
-CROW: He's a Who.
-Who grows to be all
of 10 feet long.
He's quite a fella.
The Indonesians calls him
the Komodo dragon.
Gene, is it possible that
one of these lizards is here?
-But somehow...
-I don't think so.
And if there were one
somehow on the loose,
it wouldn't be
what you're looking for.
The Komodo dragon
walks on four feet.
-This...
-CROW: Scene is dying.
...indicates a lizard
that can walk upright.
Some form of reptile...
-CROW: Yes.
-...closely related
to the Tyrannosaurus Rex.
SERVO: The T-Rex
has the classic pear shape.
MIKE: Some describe me
as an ambulatory mound of suet.
Thanks, Johnny.
But how in the hell
am I gonna tell the commissioner
or anyone down at city hall
that a man was killed
on the doorstep
of his own home last night
by some kind of dinosaur?
[ Music playing ]
CROW:
Thanks for the stereotype music.
SERVO:
The meter's running, lady.
[ Music playing ]
SERVO:
Johnny, Johnny Longbone,
Johnny, Johnny Longbone.
It's the Johnny Longbone.
Johnny Longbone theme.
MIKE: Bobby Sherman looks on.
How do you feel today, Paul?
A whole lot better
than yesterday.
CROW: Who cares?
-Hi.
Hey, they're pretty good.
But you should see Johnny
work with the bow.
-CROW: Whoa.
-Our scholarly
anthropologist here
was the conference
archery champ in college.
-I've seen his trophies.
-CROW: In the locker room.
How about a little demonstration
for our camp?
All right.
Come on, Johnny Longbow.
I'd like to see you live up
to your name.
SERVO: Hi-yo, get the kids
out of the room.
CROW: I swiped these
from that Indian
while he was crying
about the garbage.
Johnny made everything himself.
SERVO: His clothes, his car.
Even the arrowheads.
Everything is authentic Indian.
MIKE: I thought everything
was Archie?
CROW: Now look
at this better stuff
-from Galleons.
-Okay, Johnny.
MIKE: Here's some toilet paper.
Now let's really impress
the lady from New York.
[ Music playing ]
SERVO: Let's share him.
[ Laughs ]
CROW: That's right,
walk in front of me
so I can see the V.P.L.
Johnny, Johnny Longbone.
Johnny, Johnny, Longbone.
[ Music playing ]
-Tonight on SOL...
-MAN: Lower please, Mike.
Okay. Tonight on S--
[ Clears throat ]
Tonight on SOL's
Legends of Rock.
MAN: Okay. Good.
MIKE: The tragic story
behind the band
that played California Lady.
The band that played
California Lady
began as a duo featuring
the fish-lipped guy
and the Eskimo.
They developed their sound
playing this kind of music
in hardscrabble bars
before a growing
circle of fans.
It wasn't until they added
the friendly looking
backup singer that the band
that played California Lady
finally hit it big
with California Lady.
The pressures of success
were huge
and the fish-lipped guy
who took on the public role
of creative genius
began to take refuge
in drinking and a new circle
of fast friends,
as he and the Eskimo
drifted apart.
That summer,
the band that played
California Lady played
before nearly 300,000
at Watkins Glen, New York,
sharing a bill with Wet Willie
and Toots and the Maytals.
Backstage, though,
the fish-lipped guy's
drinking was beginning
to get out of hand.
Creative tensions mounted
and a haze of alcohol
served only to cover up
the Eskimo's
increasing drug use.
It was a hopeful sign
when the friendly-looking
backup singer checked
into a rehab clinic
to have her blood replaced
but the fish-lipped guy's
out-of-control
womanizing led the Eskimo
into an ever more deadly
spiral of drug use and drink.
Drug-addled recording sessions
produced the band
that played California Lady's
follow-up album,
the more melodic
Rhode Island Lady,
but it failed
to crack the charts
as the band that played
California Lady's
audience did not follow them
into this new territory.
By this time, the drugs, booze
and womanizing
had begun to replace the music.
Friends were troubled
as an opportunity to open
for Brewer and Shipley
on a world tour
went by the boards
when the Eskimo
slipped into a long-term
alcoholic coma.
The fish-lipped guy
turned increasingly to booze,
drugs, womanizing
and out-of-control gambling
and the band that played
California Lady
was no more.
Happily, the last year
has seen a reunion
and a new generation of fans
have discovered the magic
that is the band
that played California Lady.
MAN: Okay. Thank you.
That's a wrap
-and we have movie sign.
-...returned
to the drinking, drugs,
-gambling, womanizing...
-MAN: Mike.
[ Doors opening ]
SERVO: Hey, how'd it go?
MIKE: I think I pulled it off.
[ Music playing ]
SERVO:
You kids should clear out.
There's gonna be some blood.
CROW:
Point to a major organ, Paul.
SERVO: Ow, corn shrapnel.
[ Clapping ]
MIKE: Hmm?
Oh, I'm sick.
I can't do the dangerous
trick anymore.
SERVO: Wuss.
CROW: Don't wreck the target.
Paul.
I think he overdid it
by coming out here today.
We've got to get him home,
Kathy.
SERVO: I'll send over some stew.
It's a fallout shelter
neighborhood.
Oh, no,
you're not talking me out
of it this time.
I'm staying.
CROW: Oh, great.
I mean oh, great.
You need looking after.
-Did you take the aspirins?
-Yes, master.
SERVO:
It's one of those relationships.
There, that's better.
Dark and restful,
you should be able to sleep now.
SERVO: I'm gonna go play
some Nine Inch Nails.
If you should need anything,
I'll be right in the den, okay?
-Okay.
-CROW: But try not to need
anything because I don't like
being bugged by you.
California me,
I'll give my love to you.
[ Music playing ]
SERVO: Oh, they could shoot
a Fiona Apple video here.
CROW: It's a hard room
to clash with,
but she manages to do it.
SERVO:
He's got an autographed picture
of Elvis Costello
and Dean Acheson.
Man, I wish she turned down
that book.
CROW: See? The bedding
is what's keeping him awake.
Look at that.
SERVO: Time to settle in
with a bound copy of TV Guide.
And now, from all of us here
at Track of the Moon Beast,
good night.
MIKE: Look over there,
its Cherry
before she gained weight.
CROW: Hmm, I wonder
how he's dying in there.
SERVO: Let's see.
How to make things pinker?
[ Music playing ]
SERVO: Good night, Keith.
CROW: I'm swimming in a pool.
Oh, no.
SERVO: I can't get
enough shots of him sick
and sweaty in bed.
CROW: I'm sick and I'm buff.
MIKE: Hey, he's got his own
confessional.
CROW: He's got a severe
allergy to shirts.
SERVO: Man, you could tuck
several more Pauls
in those pajamas.
CROW: But don't.
MIKE: Mom.
Mom, did Santa get here yet?
SERVO: Oh look,
she's sleeping so pinkfully.
CROW: This film is lit
with a spelunker's headlamp.
[ Heavy breathing ]
-SERVO: Punk.
-CROW: Ow.
MIKE: Louie Anderson
sits bath.
SERVO: I'm gonna do
a quick can opener,
then I can go back to bed.
MIKE: Sounds like Lurch
is playing the bad guy.
CROW: When did we switch
to realtor's walkthrough
point of view?
-SERVO: Clonk.
-CROW: Ow.
SERVO: Drink me in, world.
I'm freshly oiled
and ready to rock.
MIKE: I'm not shirtless enough.
I'm gonna take off my skin.
CROW:
That's just a picture of a moon.
SERVO: Yeah, the moon
backed out of this movie
at the last minute.
MAN: I'll open it.
Okay, then. I'll open it.
I'll open it.
Wait just a minute.
-SERVO: Hello?
-CROW: Hello?
SERVO:
Are we invited to your movie?
MAN: You're in for two.
How about you, Earl?
-EARL: Yeah.
-MAN: Okay.
- How many cards...
-SERVO: Some casinos
started off on a modest scale.
MAN: They'll never win
this game...
never win this game, friend.
SERVO: Yes, it's Gabe Kaplan's
poker camp for kids.
MAN: Okay, two for you
and two winning cards
for the big winner
of the night.
Okay?
SERVO: Don't touch the side
of the tent, now it'll leak.
[ Screaming ]
CROW: Let's party. Hoo hoo.
SERVO: Norman Rockwell.
CROW: Whose arm is this?
Anyone wanna claim this arm?
SERVO: Arm? No.
Paul. Paul.
SERVO: Where did those
leftover body parts
in the fridge come from?
CROW:
It's our 24-hour anniversary.
When I woke up, I couldn't
find you anywhere in the house.
I got so worried.
What are you doing out here?
SERVO: I'm stuck
to the chaise lounge
[ Slurps ]
It was so warm in my room.
CROW: So I killed
a tent full of old guys.
I couldn't get back to sleep.
Well, it must've been
chilly out here last night.
You could've caught cold.
SERVO: Man, there's a shrill
pink lump next to me.
All you men are alike.
Sometimes you act
like such big babies.
CROW: They spit up
formula all over me...
Come on.
I'll make you some breakfast.
MACK: He was still alive
when we found him.
SERVO:
Who, the eight of diamonds?
MIKE: I fold.
The man was pretty far gone
in shock,
but he did manage to say
something
about a lizard, a big lizard,
a big lizard that walked
like a man.
-SERVO: Yeah, okay.
-Seems to me
I've heard that
expression before.
Maybe.
Something your friend Deets
said about a dinosaur.
A Tyrannosaurus.
CROW: Actually, a Paulosaurus.
Well, there have been
discoveries of supposedly
extinct creatures dating back
to the dinosaur age.
SERVO: But screw you, man.
Ancient life forms
that are still alive today.
MIKE: Okay, I'm going gray
but I'm not
an ancient life form.
Maybe there is a dinosaur
still alive...
CROW: Hey, Steve.
...up in the hills.
Hurry up, slowpoke.
I wanna get you off my hands,
then your lady can take over.
PAUL: Johnny,
you're one hell of a guy.
White man speak
with forked tongue.
Oh, quick,
let me write that down.
Hurry up, will you?
I got other things to do.
CROW: I have to name
stew ingredients.
What happened here, where's Ty?
MIKE: Tie is with jacket.
I don't know.
He must've broken out
the night before last.
Something scared him.
SERVO: It was my serial
shirtlessness.
Maybe the meteor shower.
CROW: I'm going to pretend
you didn't even say that.
Is this the meteorite you found?
PAUL: Small personal moon rock.
SERVO:
Your own personal
moon rock.
PAUL: Funny thing.
I've looked through every text
I have on mineralogy...
MIKE: Well, the one I have.
...and I can't find
anything like it.
CROW: Nor can I find
a decent deodorant.
Of course, I haven't run
a series of tests on it.
You mind if I borrow
your moon rock
-for a couple of days?
-SERVO: Sure, take the key.
Go ahead.
I was gonna take it
to the geology lab anyway.
Maybe they can find
the answer to it.
I can't.
But right now, we're gonna
take you over to St. Joe's.
Maybe they can find an answer
to what's been bugging you.
...wait in his office.
Thanks.
How do you feel?
Not bad.
Good.
While you're waiting,
I might as well do
an errand near here.
-I'll be back in a little while.
-No sweat.
MIKE: I'm gonna go
get my bone longing.
JOHNNY: Then it's not just some
kind of error
in printing, Mr. Harold.
Definitely not.
I remember looking
at the originals
on that roll myself.
CROW: Mother and I looked at it.
What you see
is what happened.
I can't explain it,
but it's not our fault
-or the fault of the film.
-SERVO: Thank you, R. Crumb.
But have you ever seen anything
like that before?
Never. And I've been
in this business for years.
CROW: Well, a year and a half.
Sutton:
Would you come this way,
please?
I've looked at your x-rays.
We don't usually discuss them
with patients.
This isn't a usual case,
Mr. Carlson.
SERVO: We'll let you in
on your illness this time.
Sutton:
just to give you an idea.
SERVO: It's a person
with a grapefruit in their head.
SUTTON: And this is the one
we took of you.
CROW: Your brain
is the size of a chickpea.
What does it mean?
What's happened to me?
You've been hit
by a small particle
of matter of some kind.
Not enough to cause any pain
because of the high speed.
But it is there.
SERVO: We also found
some stray Q-tips.
Then, something's
inside my head?
-Yes.
-CROW: Not much but...
It's not uncommon.
There have been cases
where servicemen
have survived
with small particles
of shrapnel embedded
in their brains.
This wasn't shrapnel, Doctor.
So I understood.
CROW: Uh-huh.
A meteorite, you said?
SERVO: I asked you,
was it a meteorite?
What happens now?
-Now?
-CROW: Mostly you die.
Now, we're gonna keep you here
for a few more days
for observation.
We're going to take
more x-rays.
If that area doesn't clear up,
we're going to do something
about it, surgically.
MIKE: He'll do a head-ectomy.
I made these photos
several years ago
when I was doing research
for my doctorate.
SERVO: I'm a Doctor of stew.
They just might have
a connection
to your killer lizard.
MIKE: Yeah,
that's what I call it.
Well, at this point,
I'd settle for anything
in the way of a lead.
Well, let's see them.
SERVO:
Show me that killer lizard.
JOHNNY: This was the first scene
in the deer hide painting
I was shown.
CROW: What kind of camera
was he using?
JOHNNY:
Not many people have seen it.
It's something like
400 years old.
What's happening
to the Indian in the painting?
MIKE: Oh, he's in the cupboard.
It's the beginning of the story.
He's being struck by a light
that comes down from the sky.
SERVO: Oh, key grip dropped it.
Well, what happened to him?
See for yourself.
Whatever struck him
from the sky
changed him completely
from human form.
MIKE: And let's see,
just more of the same,
some pictures
from when I went to Cancun.
JOHNNY: He became
a demon-lizard monster.
Arrows had no effect on him.
Well, how'd they get rid of this
demon lizard?
They didn't.
But he died anyway.
SERVO:
Kind of a dumb legend, really.
JOHNNY: It is consumed by fire.
But where the flames came from,
nobody knows.
SERVO: How do you light
your own back on fire?
MIKE: Surprise,
it was me running the slides.
That's the mystery
and it's still a mystery...
After 400 years.
CROW: Now I'm over here.
I know what you're thinking.
SERVO: I'm boring
and my slideshow eats.
It's only an Indian legend,
part of our tribal culture.
Oh, I know, it's fantastic.
That is the one thing
that ties in
with what the fisherman said.
CROW: He said, "I got one."
He said the camp was attacked
by a lizard
that walked like a man.
MIKE: Michael Douglas?
CROW: Sheriff...
I want your help, Mack.
SERVO: My garage door opener
doesn't work.
CROW: Come on,
I can get a free hot lunch
at my kid's school.
Well, we've got the place
to ourselves.
I had them close up early
on my authority...
this proves something.
MIKE: I haven't solved
a case in years.
They'll know in a minute.
I never thought I'd see
the day when I try to solve
a case with Indian superstition.
SERVO: Johnny, you mind?
We are just about to find out.
MIKE: I am gonna beat
the stuffing out of you.
SERVO:
Longbone goes into his windup.
JOHNNY: It should be
somewhere just about...
CROW: Would you finish
a sentence?
...here.
-[ Beeps ]
-What was that?
-I don't really know.
-MIKE: Let me make up
a quick legend.
My guess is that there's some...
SERVO: Peanut butter?
...unusual element
in this fragment
that synchronizes with that
larger mass over there.
CROW: Oh, that's the folk mass.
They get more people.
Kind of produces some kind of
energy reaction.
-MIKE: Let's just go eat.
-You mean this energy
or whatever it is
can turn a human into a monster?
SERVO: Would turn a manwich
into a meal.
Just like in those
werewolf tales,
when there's a full moon
in Transylvania?
Johnny, I have known you
for a long time,
but you got to be kidding.
I wish I was kidding, Mack.
CROW: This hair doesn't lie.
I'm not.
Now, there is an answer
and I think I know what it is.
MIKE: I copied from the Indian
sitting next to me.
And it makes me sick
to think about it.
CROW:
Soon I'll be throwing up corn,
green pepper, chicken, onions.
If what you say is true...
SERVO: Indians were here first?
...the x-rays,
the way the meteorite reacted
and your Indian legend...
MIKE: Is meteowrong, I'd say.
...and there's something
I've got to know
for my own peace of mind.
CROW: Granted,
it's a small piece.
JOHNNY: He's right, Paul.
Nobody knows what might happen.
SERVO: Except for Faith Popcorn.
Let's find out.
How much time do I have?
It'll be sundown
in half an hour.
MIKE: We can go to the drive-in.
The moon will be up
in an hour or so after then.
CROW: Of course,
that's just an old chubby
white sheriff's legend.
Before anything happens,
I wanna talk to Kathy.
I'm sure that can be arranged.
She's at the reservation,
I'll phone right now.
SERVO: Call me Johnny
Long-phone-her-
at-the-reservation-bone.
MIKE: Sheriff,
will you give me a sponge bath?
CROW: I hope they have
boiled chicken
and tapioca for lunch.
[ Buzzing ]
MACK:
You better give her some idea
of what he might have
to go through,
-just to prepare.
-JOHNNY: I'll try.
SERVO: She's not the sharpest
knife in the drawer.
Kathy, let me talk to you...
We've had to move Paul
to another room.
-He's in there.
-Why is he in there?
Why are these policemen here?
We're not sure
what may happen to Paul
after the moonrise.
In fact, moving him here
was his idea.
-But, surely...
-Kathy.
See, this is a hospital.
We can't afford
to take any chances.
MIKE: And we can't afford
a boom mic.
The moon has a strong effect
on the earth.
Look what it can do the tides.
CROW: And look
at what Tide can for stains.
In Paul's case,
it may trigger a whole set
of changes,
a temporary mutation...
I want to see him.
Now, please.
SERVO: I've known him
for eight hours.
I think I deserve to see him.
MIKE: So how's the pretending
you're not old going?
CROW:
His condition is so grave
that he's confined
to the ironing board.
SERVO: I see he's wearing
his Doris Day PJs.
CROW: I was dreaming
and then suddenly Judith Light
appeared over my bed.
SERVO: Wow, big cockroach
on the wall back there.
CROW: Whoo, mama.
[ Music playing ]
CROW: Nice hallway, anyway.
It's nearly sundown now.
She shouldn't be in there
much longer.
All right, I'll get her.
Kathy?
SERVO: Decouple and come on out.
Kathy.
MIKE: Get the hose, officer.
CROW: Kathy,
your skirt's on backwards.
-Thanks, Johnny.
-Can I take you home?
SERVO: As long as
you're giving it away.
No. Thank you, anyway.
It's no trouble, miss.
One of my men
can take you home.
MIKE: Guys are lining up
to take her home.
Thank you, captain,
I'll be all right.
I'd like to stay here
at the hospital.
CROW:
Well, I could take you there.
Look, I really wanna take
you somewhere.
MIKE: I'd almost unhook
my thumbs for her.
SERVO: Ladies and gentlemen,
Seth Thomas,
the best actor in the film.
[ Music playing ]
MIKE: There he is again.
How can you tell what time it
is when those little sticks
keep moving around like that?
The moon is up now.
I hope you're right.
I don't.
I hope I'm wrong.
SERVO: Johnny, let's not fight.
Well, we'll know
in a few minutes.
Something's happening.
-SERVO: Let me see.
-Oh, my God.
CROW: They leaned his bed
against the wall
so they could vacuum.
SERVO: I'm sorry,
nothing's happening. Never mind.
MIKE: Wow.
He's transforming
into the exact same person.
CROW: Ah, he's becoming
Michael Ontkean,
and then Michael Nouri,
and then Michael Parks.
SERVO: Ugh.
He's turning into Roy Scheider.
MIKE: I'm ready to fight
Captain Kirk.
SERVO: And now this from
Pond's Cold Cream.
Man, watching you turn
into a moon beast
was like watching paint dry.
MIKE: Are you supposed to put
your head through that hole
and get your picture taken?
Then it's true.
CROW: Wearing Underoos is fun.
It was me.
I killed all of those people?
Now it wasn't your fault, son.
SERVO: You're free to go.
They won't convict you,
they won't even blame you
once the people know the facts.
We'll soon have you back
to normal, Paul.
MIKE: Tomorrow we'll be
laughing about your killings.
-Do I need these now?
-No.
CROW: But, Paul, do you have
to leave your victims
in humorous poses?
Dr. Sutton has been in touch
with NASA about your case.
They're sending one of their
top lunar scientists
and one of the finest brain
surgeons in the country.
SERVO:
Maybe you could kill them.
See that particle of meteor
in the front part of your brain,
it's causing the problem.
When it's removed, you won't
have a thing to worry about.
You can go back to leading
your normal life.
MIKE: Oh, you're gonna kill me?
I'd like to see Kathy.
CROW: And I'd like to see
Marmaduke.
Please.
SERVO:
Ah, you horny serial killer you.
CROW: Guess what, I'm
a vicious killer, but it's okay.
Kathy.
MIKE: Ugh.
SERVO: Well, we'll go stand
out in the hall again.
MIKE: Yeah, it's boinking
guard for the losers.
CROW: Guests of Track
of the Moon Beast fly TWA.
SERVO: Does anyone
need a food cart to crap on?
Would you fasten
your seatbelts, please?
We'll be landing shortly.
When are we due in Albuquerque?
In about 20 minutes.
The captain got a message
a few minutes ago.
You and Dr. Lawrence
will be met at the airport.
Thank you.
May we get off first, please.
We just have some hand luggage.
ATTENDANT:
That's also been arranged.
You and Dr. Rizzo are to be
given every cooperation.
MIKE: I must get to my Skitch
Henderson convention.
I must admit, I was pretty
startled last night
-when I got the call.
-So was I.
I've never come up against
a case anything like it
and I've had a few unusual ones,
I must say.
We've been worried at NASA
all through the Apollo Program
about the possibility
that something
could cause a mutated life form.
Nothing ever happened.
Until now.
CROW: Hey did you hear
about Niels Bohr and his wife?
[ Indistinct chatter ]
Hello, Paul, this is Dr. Rizzo.
-SERVO: What up, bitch?
-How are you, Paul?
I'm going to be operating
on you in just a little while.
I'm glad to see you.
What happens now?
We're going to make
another set of x-rays
just to check on the particle.
The new set will give
us an exact pinpointing
of the spot in the left frontal
lobe where it is.
MIKE: Then my doppelganger
will give you an MRI.
CROW: You removed the wrong leg!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought you should see
these right away, doctor.
I think we should look
at these inside.
SERVO: Inside the topless
bar on the corner.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
But I'll try to find out.
CROW: Yes, he has
confetti in his head.
DR. RIZZO:
If you look at the difference
in the affected areas.
SERVO: You'll learn nothing.
DR. RIZZO: You'll notice
considerable change, doctor.
There's been a definite growth.
MIKE: In my bald spot.
DR. LAWRENCE: From the
look of it, I'd say the particle
in that young man's brain
has disintegrated
and energy factors are spreading
through his entire system.
DR. RIZZO: No question about it.
SERVO: You're an idiot.
Isn't there any way of, well,
neutralizing the effect, doctor?
SERVO: Barking at us,
what is he saying?
That's your field, Dr. Lawrence.
Isn't there something
that can be done?
We're dealing with a brand
new unstable element here.
-One we've never seen before.
-MIKE: So we give up.
We don't know its
characteristics,
atomic structure, how it reacts.
There's a chance.
There's always a chance.
Eventually, by doing research
on the meteorite fragments
you showed me.
SERVO:
Can I have a glass of water?
DR. LAWRENCE:
Well we might learn how...
[ Doors closing ]
Eagle one to base,
eagle one to base.
Position of mobile personnel
reconnaissance robot unknown.
Repeat, position unknown.
Do not attempt to...
I'm right here, Crow.
Oh. Well, maybe you know
the position of the mobile
personnel reconnaissance robot?
You mean the little toy truck
with the camera taped to it?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, I got it. Okay.
Mike's headed in for a nap
and our little friend
is right behind.
Soon after all these years,
we'll know what kind of pajamas
our enigmatic pal wears.
Yeah.
And then we can kill him.
No, Crow.
Oh, right.
I was thinking of someone else.
I'm sorry.
Okay. Switching to video feed
from recon robot now.
-Ah-hah.
-CROW: There he is.
Oh, man.
He's wearing a robe.
SERVO: What,
is he Fred MacMurray?
Take off the damn robe, Mike.
Oh, look at this.
CROW:
Yeah, you're working out.
Good job, grandpa.
SERVO: I don't know.
Maybe we should turn this off.
CROW: Oh, no. No, it's his fault
for not suspecting
that we would build
a sophisticated robot to spy
on his undergarments.
SERVO: I guess.
Oh, look, he's putting
on a playlet of some sort
with his stuffed animals.
CROW: Okay.
Let's get a closer look.
Although I can't be sure,
it appears that the bear
is upset with his position
on the bed and is vituperating
the young rabbit.
I'll have more information
on this as we...
SERVO: Forget about that.
He's on the move.
-He's taking off his robe.
-CROW: Oh, that's it.
That's it. Take it off, baby.
Daddy like.
Dribble out
of those Bobbie Brooks.
SERVO:
Oh, no, we're made. We're made.
Switching off feed.
Okay. Act natural.
Act natural.
What? What, Mike?
What is your problem?
What are you accusing us of?
Yeah.
My robots, always stalking
me while I sleep.
We'll be right back.
-Take off your robe.
-[ Shushing ]
Oh, no. Sorry. Nothing.
Really, sorry.
[ Music playing ]
Then...
the energy
is released all at once.
MIKE: You guys.
A form of explosion.
Exactly.
And when it happens,
your young friend
will be consumed by...
CROW: Well, it was great
meeting you, okay?
I've got to talk to you now.
Let's go.
MIKE: Where did you get
that anatomy chart?
The demon in
the tribal painting.
CROW: We were lovers once.
Self-consumed.
SERVO:
That's a soccer team for you.
One Indian mystery solved.
MIKE: Tonight on 'Sightings'.
KATHY: Oh, Paul. Why
couldn't there be time for us?
CROW: Well, how much time
do you need?
There isn't...
and that's why I am
going away now.
SERVO: Because you want
to go out with me.
If I'm gonna die.
MIKE: Let it be as a blonde.
I wanna die looking like a man.
CROW: In my feetie pajamas.
Not like a monster.
KATHY: Paul, don't.
SERVO: Oh, where did you get
the second row of teeth?
I'm sorry I regurgitated
that mouse into your mouth.
I need a few minutes.
CROW: I have to squirm out
of my old skin.
I've got to get away from here.
KATHY: Get away where?
SERVO: Oh, maybe they got
an opening at Reptile Garden.
I don't know,
but I can't stand being
locked up here again.
MIKE: In this coat closet.
KATHY: Will I see you again?
CROW: Maybe, but I'll be
blended into my background.
I don't know.
SERVO: Just buy a gecko
to remember me by.
And I want you to go back
to Dr. Sutton's office.
MIKE: Dr. Frank Sutton.
And if anybody asks...
CROW: We barely know each other.
...where I am,
I want you tell them
I'm on the roof.
That'll keep them busy
enough for a few minutes,
long enough for me.
-I won't do it.
-Kathy.
SERVO: Okay. I will.
Please, do it for my sake.
MIKE: Wear pink hot pants
to my funeral.
Do it because
we love each other.
CROW:
And they proceed to do it
because they love each other.
SERVO: Mm-hmm.
Oh, Paul.
Why did this
have to happen to you?
SERVO:
The finest man in the world.
MIKE: And by the way,
when you meet my mom,
could you let her know
I turned into a lizard?
It did happen.
CROW:
You just didn't feel it.
That's all I know.
SERVO: Uh-huh. Now an ambulance
goes in the emergency entrance.
I get it.
MIKE: Ah, I had to kill
a doctor to get this,
but it seems to be okay.
CROW:
Eventually, I will crash.
I'll just do it here,
save some trouble.
SERVO: They got a bunch
of livers stacked up.
MIKE: Free, please take.
CROW:
Yeah, I'll mosey inside.
I'm just having
a small aneurysm.
Yup.
SERVO: I'm gonna go find
the nearest rock
in the sun to lay on.
[ Motorcycle revving ]
MIKE: Man, thing's almost
as loud as a leaf blower.
Stunts I've ever seen.
Does that kid think
he can get away?
CROW: No, sir.
KATHY:
He's not trying to get away.
SERVO: Wait, wait.
There she is.
You don't understand.
You just don't.
MIKE: We made out a lot.
CROW: I need a wheat
penny and a Glock.
MAN: A search has begun
to locate a young...
Yes, sir?
What can I do for you?
I'd like a 12-gauge shotgun.
-SERVO: And a licorice whip.
-And some shells.
Well, we have some very nice
models just came in.
Very nice guns. I'll be glad
to show them to you.
MIKE: Should I wait a few
days and cool off?
-SERVO: No, no reason.
-MIKE: All right.
MAN:
Here's a description of the man
being sought whose name
is Paul G. Carlson.
He's 24 years old, Caucasian,
about six feet tall.
Weighing 160, brown hair.
-Here's a nice one.
-MAN: Blue eyes.
CROW: Oh, my eyes are going,
I keep imagining
muscular young men.
MAN: Paul was last seen
in the vicinity of St.
Joseph Hospital.
He is believed dressed in tan
slacks and a blue sweater.
SERVO: Again,
the birthday calls, damn it.
We got a report on him.
Owner of a gun shop,
says he tried to buy a shotgun
but left without it.
SERVO: Any thoughts bobbin
head baseball kid?
I don't think he wants
it as a weapon.
He wants to kill himself.
-CROW: Too bad new girlfriend.
-Why, Ms. Nolan?
SERVO:
Why can't I drive you home?
Because we overheard
what Dr. Lawrence
said in the other office.
CROW: That's why patients
shouldn't be told anything.
That's why.
You might be wrong, Mac.
SERVO: Hard to say, chum.
He's on a motorcycle.
If he wanted to kill himself...
No, no, no, crashes don't
always kill people.
-He knows that.
-SERVO: Wrong again, Johnny.
Now he'd try to find some way
that was fast and foolproof.
CROW: Or noisy
and very likely to fail.
SERVO: I'm being chased
by a huge bee.
[ Imitates bee buzzing ]
If only we had some kind
of lead on him.
Anything.
MIKE: Brain has performed
an illegal operation
and will be shut down.
PAUL: Yeah, I like to come
up here at night.
CROW: What?
It's one of my favorite
places on earth.
-CROW: What?
-PAUL: It's always so peaceful.
-PAUL: So quiet.
CROW: What?
MIKE: Thinking hurts. Ow.
I can't stand
this waiting around.
CROW: I'm gonna get
a different boyfriend.
I think it would be better
if I went back
-to the reservation, don't you?
-I guess so.
SERVO: Although I have
reservations about it.
Well, how will you get back?
I borrowed Budd's car.
MIKE: Well, find out
who Budd is and return it.
I'll phone you
if we hear anything.
CROW: There's a legend
of a lizard with a phone.
It goes like--
[ Humming ]
SERVO: A toad.
MIKE: Oh, well. I'll just grow
another one of those.
CROW: Um, the end?
-Might I suggest?
-SERVO: Please.
[ Music playing ]
SERVO:
I'm in heaven. Oh, no. Crap.
CROW: His pants are Haggar
and they're horrible.
SERVO: Oh, man.
Ski conditions suck.
MIKE: Over there, ma'am,
is New Mexico
and, oh, over there
you'll see Mexico.
CROW: Enjoy our onboard
clavichord concert.
SERVO: Hey, everybody,
let's throw water balloons
on Georgia O'Keeffe.
[ Screaming ]
SERVO: I'm fine.
I know what I'm doing.
CROW: On second thought,
maybe I'll just go
have the meteor extracted.
-They found the motorcycle.
-JOHNNY: Where?
MCCABE: Up in State Road 44.
He took a spill.
SERVO:
A guy picked up his hat.
MCCABE: The bike is a wreck.
But he probably
walked away all right.
They couldn't find him
anywhere around the area.
That road leads up
to Sandia Crest.
MIKE: Yes.
Of course, that's got to be it.
Over the years,
I got to know Paul pretty well.
MIKE: The other Beatles
were kind of aloof.
The one place he went to when
he was troubled,
the one place
where he felt free
was Sandia Crest.
CROW: I feel free.
Ow.
SERVO: Baretta.
MIKE: Actually,
most people in New Mexico
think about killing
themselves two,
three times a week.
CROW: Ah, I should've brought
the Wet Vac to scoop him up.
SERVO: Okay. Oh, yeah.
There's his normal head
injury spot right there.
MIKE: Let me get
my car Simonized
and then I'll be right back.
[ Music playing ]
CROW: Get your kicks on me.
MCCABE: Right, Pete,
get to Sandia Crest.
Now, listen...
SERVO: You can actually hear
my lunch digesting.
MAN: ...I want him captured,
but no gun play.
MIKE: Can we do a passion play?
MCCABE: Unless
it's absolutely necessary.
CROW: You can put nightsticks
wherever you want, though.
That's fine.
SERVO: If I catch
his death on tape,
I can send it to Fox.
MIKE: She even has a tawny car.
SERVO: Okay. Careful,
check both ways, look out.
Good.
Now, I can [ Makes noise ]
boom, boom.
Oh, Paul.
CROW:
Your pants are killing you.
Oh, Paul.
For a minute
I thought you were...
MIKE: Someone I like.
SERVO: He's dead.
I know what you intend to do,
but you mustn't.
Please, you can't.
Kathy, I don't know
how you found me,
but you've got to leave now.
CROW: My vent is opening, go.
No, Paul.
I wanna be with you.
You can't stay.
The sun's going down.
MIKE:
My sun tea will be ruined.
It'll be night soon.
If I don't reach the Crest...
SERVO: Or another
effective dentifrice.
...before the moon comes up.
You can't stay.
CROW: My other girlfriend
is coming to roll down
the hill with me.
Then it will be...
too late for the both of us.
MIKE: Well, you're the lizard,
I think it's more
too late for you.
CROW: I'm gonna go forage
for tighter pants.
MIKE:
I lost my Christmas wreath.
MCCABE:
Any sign of them, Pete?
No, sir. But we'll keep
checking the area.
All right. You stay put.
We'll check down the hill
a little further.
If anything happens,
call me fast.
-Yes, sir.
-SERVO: Fat bastard.
I mean, yes, sir.
SERVO: The sun is rising.
CROW: A huge flying squid
must've just ejected his ink
all over the moon there.
Paul?
-Paul, help me.
-CROW: What? Who?
Paul? Paul, please.
SERVO: Try standing up.
Help me, Paul.
Please, help me.
PAUL: No.
KATHY: Help me.
SERVO: Paul or Spock, help me.
KATHY: Paul. Paul. Paul.
CROW: This is hard, I should've
just bought that shotgun.
KATHY: Paul, help me.
SERVO: I hope she says,
"Paul, help me" again real soon.
-CROW: Yeah.
-KATHY: Paul.
MIKE: My Earth shoes
are slippery.
Please, Paul,
my foot is cut, help me.
CROW: Come on, Paul pizza face.
Paul, help me.
Please.
MIKE: I mean, how'd we reach
the top the first time?
That was so easy.
CROW: Bet I can palm this rock.
He's just got Elli Nails.
MIKE: Oh, he's turning
into a great NFL receiver.
They all have big hands.
SERVO: Oh, oh, big nails.
Oh, oh.
[ Screaming ]
CROW:
His hands are big I know,
but they are not yours, they...
MIKE: Oh, monstrous pigs
are attacking.
CROW:
Is the scene over or--okay.
I'm headed over
to craft services.
[ Screaming ]
SERVO: Ah, hell,
let's just shoot up there
and see what happens.
[ Gunshots ]
CROW: They've shot two
klieg lights and a gaffer.
MIKE: Ah, what the heck.
I could use a little
administrative leave.
[ Police siren wailing ]
SERVO: And they bring
in a little kid with a huge jar
with holes poked in the top.
CROW: They're being chased
by the Johnson family.
MIKE: Things sure are happening
over in that direction.
SERVO: Come here
you knuckle knobs.
What? Oh,
I play too rough, don't I?
CROW: Oh, God.
I'm relaxed.
MIKE: Stupid professor was
kicking my seat the whole way.
-Kathy.
-SERVO: Bonbon.
CROW: Easy, cop. He's a Rabbi.
They're cops,
except for the Rabbi.
MIKE: I'd help, but my thumbs
are occupied.
What happened?
Where's Paul?
He got away.
Two more men are dead.
SERVO: That's our goal.
Oh, God.
It's too late to help Paul.
Not now.
He's got to be stopped before
there's any more killing.
CROW: Good luck with that.
I'll see you.
SERVO: This is no time
to play the oud.
Are you gonna try and stop it
with a bow and arrow?
Not just with any arrow, Mac.
-I'm going to use this.
-CROW: A really good arrow.
That looks like a piece
of the meteor Paul had.
It is.
I fashioned
an arrowhead out of it.
MIKE: Is that someone's beeper?
What are you going to do?
SERVO: Shoot your boyfriend,
then come onto you.
Johnny, tell me.
We're fighting something
we barely understand, Kathy.
CROW: Esperanto.
The changes
that a particle of matter
from outer space has made
in a human being.
That's why I'm doing this.
If a particle can generate
all that energy
the larger piece
from the same element
might speed up
the energy processes.
SERVO: Hey, hands off.
Dr. Lawrence, Paul and I
heard you in the hospital.
You said Paul would become
atomically unstable,
that he would...
It was always inevitable.
This way it may happen
a little sooner, that's all.
SERVO: Do you always have egg
in your beard?
Johnny, you can't do it.
He's your friend. Paul...
Paul is not Paul anymore.
CROW: He's Super Paul.
Kathy, he's not as you
and I know him.
MIKE: He's smart and funny.
Paul is gone.
What you see in his place
is nothing we know,
nothing human.
MIKE: God, I'm acting.
[ Screaming ]
No!
CROW: Jesus, they're acting
all over the place now.
MIKE: And the actors begin
abandoning the movie one by one.
CROW: I got to pick up
the kids from soccer.
That poor kid.
SERVO:
She's never known my love.
She's had a rough time.
CROW: I'll find him
at the all-night fly store.
[ Screaming ]
SERVO: The Beatles.
CROW: Just go
around me, ma'am.
There you go.
SERVO: Got her.
No, no.
MIKE: I think she said,
"Blah, blah."
CROW: The arrow
caused him to Frug.
SERVO: It's cozy watching
your boyfriend die.
♪ And the monster's
red glare ♪
MIKE:
Hey, I'm in a Buggles video.
CROW: This was inevitable.
MIKE: I'm gonna have
a pork chop for dinner.
CROW: The sad thing is,
is he'll miss my stew
made with corn, green peppers,
chicken, onions.
Did this community ban
outdoor lizard burning?
MIKE: What an idiot, huh?
Now, let's go.
CROW: Okay. We'll see you.
MIKE: Kathy, can I hook
my thumbs in your belt?
CROW: Well, I learned something
from this movie, you guys.
-SERVO: Yeah, Crow?
-CROW: Yeah. I learned my vomit
can rise pretty high and I can
still tamp it down.
MIKE:
Oh, hang on to that, Crow.
That's a--
that's a good talent.
CROW: Yeah.
SERVO: Bom, bom.
CROW: There's thumb harnesses
on the dashboard for him.
MIKE: Oh, crap. Look at that,
I hit his car, let's go.
-CROW: Hurry.
-MIKE: Come on, go.
SERVO: I see a huge casino.
MIKE: Now, come on now.
[ Doors closing ]
[ Sobbing ]
Servo, what's wrong?
What's the matter?
Oh, Mike.
I was playing with my bow
and arrow, you know.
I was pretending like
I was hunting, you know.
It's my bow and arrow, you
know, so I shot my arrow,
you know, just like
I was hunting, you know.
And I accidently hit
a little satellite.
Well, that's okay, Servo.
But I guess you've learned
a little lesson
about the fragility
-of satellite communications.
-Yeah.
And the delicate balance
of technology.
Yeah.
I have, Mike, I'm sorry.
It's all right. You know what?
I think he's gonna be okay.
I think we just have to feed
him and take care of him,
and he'll be fine.
But his mom is gonna miss him.
Oh, Servo, don't be silly.
It's just a satellite.
Satellites don't have moth--
Huh?
Hello.
Here, Mrs. Satellite.
-Fly, fly.
-Hello. Communicate, go, go.
Big.
And so your antistatic cleaner
is the best bet for keeping
your brain clean.
It's sort of like a surge
protector for the old bean.
-Oh, you.
-Here you go.
You know, Brain Guy,
you've been so helpful
and so supportive what with me
and my new exposed
brain and all.
-Thank you so much.
-Oh, hell, I've been there.
-Oh, you certainly.
-Oh, oh, wait.
If I find if I'm going to be
away from The Brain
for more than a few minutes,
I like to put the club on it.
You can't be too
careful these days.
Oh, you certainly can't,
old buddy.
We need you jerk.
Take that back, you idiot.
Oh, says you?
I really hate to see
them getting along.
You ignoramus.
You stupid head.
Troglodyte.
You dodo head.
Credit risk.
You dummy head.
[ Music playing ]
Moon rock? Oh, wow.